{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "201.Which state launched the \u2018Patch Reporting App\u2019 to make the roads in state free of pot holes?",
            "options": [
                "Uttarakhand",
                "Assam",
                "Gujarat",
                "Bihar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Uttarakhand"
        },
        {
            "question": "202.Open Network for Digital Commerce (ONDC) is an interoperable network based on the whichprotocol?",
            "options": [
                "BeckN",
                "XML",
                "Graph QL",
                "SOAP"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "BeckN"
        },
        {
            "question": "203.Which country has been recently hit by \u2018African Plume Heatwave\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "UK",
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "Brazil"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UK"
        },
        {
            "question": "204.Dal Lake, which was seen in the news, is located in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Assam",
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Karnataka",
                "Uttarakhand"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
        },
        {
            "question": "205.Where is the \u2018Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum\u2019 located?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Japan",
                "China",
                "Russia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Japan"
        },
        {
            "question": "206.Bakhmut, which was seen in the news, is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "Ukraine",
                "France",
                "Germany"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ukraine"
        },
        {
            "question": "207.Where is the \u2018Rajaji Tiger Reserve\u2019 located in India?",
            "options": [
                "Gujarat",
                "Uttarakhand",
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "Maharashtra"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Uttarakhand"
        },
        {
            "question": "209.Who is the new Deputy Chief Minister of Karnataka?",
            "options": [
                "DK Shivakumar",
                "Siddaramaiah",
                "Thawar Chand Gehlot &#160; &#160;",
                "Basavaraj Horatti"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "DK Shivakumar"
        },
        {
            "question": "210.\u2018Sendai Framework\u2019, which was seen in the news, is associated with which field?",
            "options": [
                "Climate Change",
                "Disaster Risk",
                "Artificial Intelligence",
                "Finance"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Disaster Risk"
        },
        {
            "question": "211.The US signed a defence cooperation agreement with which country?",
            "options": [
                "Indonesia",
                "Papua New Guinea",
                "Australia",
                "Singapore"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Papua New Guinea"
        },
        {
            "question": "212.Which country\u2019s researchers have developed e-skin that can help amputees experience touch?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "Israel"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "214.What is the name of the central programme launched to promote artificial intelligence in Indiaand beyond?",
            "options": [
                "BharatAI",
                "INDIAai",
                "BHIMai",
                "VIKASai"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "INDIAai"
        },
        {
            "question": "215.Which Indian city is placed among the top three data centre markets in Asia-Pacific region?",
            "options": [
                "Mumbai",
                "Chennai",
                "New Delhi",
                "Bengaluru"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mumbai"
        },
        {
            "question": "216.Machilipatnam port project was launched recently by which state?",
            "options": [
                "Andhra Pradesh",
                "Tamil Nadu",
                "Kerala",
                "Odisha"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Andhra Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "217.Which state\/UT launched the Mukhyamantri Teerthdarshan Yojana?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "Gujarat",
                "Uttarakhand"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Madhya Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "218.Which institution released the \u2018Atlas of Mortality and Economic Losses from Weather, Climateand Water-related hazards\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "UNEP",
                "WMO",
                "WTO",
                "World Bank"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "WMO"
        },
        {
            "question": "219.Which institution released the report titled \u201cThriving: Making Cities Green, Resilient, andInclusive in a Changing Climate\u201d?",
            "options": [
                "WMO",
                "WTO",
                "World Bank",
                "UNEP"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "World Bank"
        },
        {
            "question": "220.Which country announced the \u201812-point development plan for the Pacific Island nations\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "China",
                "Bangladesh",
                "India",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "India"
        },
        {
            "question": "221.Colorado River flows through which country?",
            "options": [
                "Argentina",
                "USA",
                "France",
                "Russia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "223.Which institution is developing \u2018Guidelines on Admissions and Quota for Disabled People\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "NMC",
                "AIIMS",
                "NMA",
                "IMA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "NMC"
        },
        {
            "question": "224.INDUS-X is a joint initiative of India and which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "UK",
                "France",
                "Italy"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "225.\u2018UDAN 5.1\u2019 scheme was launched by which Union Ministry?",
            "options": [
                "Ministry of Civil Aviation",
                "Ministry of MSME",
                "Ministry of Defence",
                "Ministry of Commerce and Industry"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ministry of Civil Aviation"
        },
        {
            "question": "226.\u2018Transport Outlook 2023\u2019 was released by which institution?",
            "options": [
                "IMF",
                "ITF",
                "WEF",
                "World Bank"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "ITF"
        },
        {
            "question": "227. ‘Orbitofrontal Cortex’ is an area in which part of the body?",
            "options": [
                "Heart",
                "Brain",
                "Muscle",
                "Liver"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Brain"
        },
        {
            "question": "228.Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals Ltd (MRPL) into Hindustan Petroleum Corp Ltd(HPCL) are the subsidiaries of which organisation?",
            "options": [
                "GAIL",
                "ONGC",
                "REC",
                "BHEL"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "ONGC"
        },
        {
            "question": "229.Where is the Global Alliance for National Human Rights Institutions (GANHRI) headquartered?",
            "options": [
                "Switzerland",
                "Moscow",
                "Paris",
                "New York"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Switzerland"
        },
        {
            "question": "230.Which city hosted the first Urban Climate Film Festival in India?",
            "options": [
                "Pune",
                "New Delhi",
                "Mumbai",
                "Mysuru"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "231.Which typhoon crossed the United States territory of Guam recently?",
            "options": [
                "Mawar",
                "Mino",
                "Mahi",
                "Myan"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mawar"
        },
        {
            "question": "232.\u2018Gerald R. Ford\u2019 the largest aircraft carrier in the world, is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Russia",
                "France",
                "Germany"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "233.\u2018Hemidactylus pakka malaiensis\u2019 is a newly discovered species belonging to?",
            "options": [
                "Turtle",
                "Gecko",
                "Spider",
                "Snake"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Gecko"
        },
        {
            "question": "234.India signed a migration pact with which country recently?",
            "options": [
                "Australia",
                "UK",
                "Singapore",
                "Malaysia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Australia"
        },
        {
            "question": "235.Carlos Alcaraz, who replaced Novak Djokovic at the No. 1 spot, is a tennis player from whichcountry?",
            "options": [
                "Spain",
                "Serbia",
                "Russia",
                "France"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "237.Which country recently launched its home-grown space rocket \u2018Nuri\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "South Korea",
                "Israel",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "South Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "238.Tina Turner, which was seen in the news, was associated with which profession?",
            "options": [
                "Author",
                "Singer",
                "Politician",
                "Sports person"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Singer"
        },
        {
            "question": "239.Special Protection Group (SPG) is the force responsible for the security of which personality?",
            "options": [
                "President",
                "Prime Minister",
                "Chief Justice of India",
                "Vice President"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Prime Minister"
        },
        {
            "question": "240.Volt Typhoon is a hacking group backed by which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "China",
                "Russia",
                "Israel"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "China"
        }
    ]
}